<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Embeddings on Muhammad Hassan Raza</title><link>https://mhassan.dev/tags/embeddings/</link><description>Recent content in Embeddings on Muhammad Hassan Raza</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mhassan.dev/tags/embeddings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Smarter FAQ Bot (with Gemini, RAG, and Structured Output)</title><link>https://mhassan.dev/blog/google-rag-smart-faq/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mhassan.dev/blog/google-rag-smart-faq/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
If you've ever found yourself digging through product manuals, company
wikis, or lengthy documents just to find a simple answer, you know the pain.
The fact you're reading this suggests you're interested in how
&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; can make that process less painful. Stick
around for a few minutes, and I'll walk you through how we built a smarter
FAQ bot using Google's Gemini API, Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), and
structured output. This isn't just another chatbot; it's designed to give
&lt;strong&gt;reliable, context-aware answers&lt;/strong&gt; based &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; on
provided information, minimizing the risk of making things up
(hallucination). This example uses Google Car manuals, but the principles
apply anywhere you have a set of documents you need to query effectively.
I'm sharing my journey building this; it's a practical demonstration, not a
definitive guide, so adapt the ideas to your needs!
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"
&gt;The Problem: Dumb Bots and Information Overload&lt;/span
&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Traditional search methods or basic chatbots often fall short when dealing
with specific document sets:
&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a Smarter FAQ Bot (with Gemini, RAG, and Structured Output)</title><link>https://mhassan.dev/blog/smart-faq-bot-google-genai-intensive-course/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 10:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mhassan.dev/blog/smart-faq-bot-google-genai-intensive-course/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
If you've ever found yourself digging through product manuals, company wikis, or lengthy documents just to find a simple answer, you know the pain. The fact you're reading this suggests you're interested in how **Generative AI** can make that process less painful. Stick around for a few minutes, and I'll walk you through how we built a smarter FAQ bot using Google's Gemini API, Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), and structured output. This isn't just another chatbot; it's designed to give **reliable, context-aware answers** based *only* on provided information, minimizing the risk of making things up (hallucination). This example uses Google Car manuals, but the principles apply anywhere you have a set of documents you need to query effectively. I'm sharing my journey building this; it's a practical demonstration, not a definitive guide, so adapt the ideas to your needs!
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-problem-dumb-bots-and-information-overload"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"&gt;The Problem: Dumb Bots and Information Overload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional search methods or basic chatbots often fall short when dealing with specific document sets:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>