<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Development on Muhammad Hassan Raza</title><link>https://mhassan.dev/tags/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on Muhammad Hassan Raza</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mhassan.dev/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final Year Project (FYP) Guide for Students</title><link>https://mhassan.dev/blog/fyp-guidance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://mhassan.dev/blog/fyp-guidance/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: justify;"&gt;
The fact that you have decided to read this behemoth of an article deserves admiration and tells me that you're serious about your academics and career (or are procrastinating on something else). Give me the next 20 mins of your life and I'll make you into a much more informed individual. Your &lt;strong&gt;Final Year Project (FYP)&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the most important academic tasks in your degree. It can shape your future career, boost your portfolio, and improve your problem-solving skills.
This guide will help you &lt;strong&gt;choose the right topic, advisor, tech stack, and strategy&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure your FYP stands out. This guide is mainly targets FASTians because of my experience, but the advice can be applied to any university. Also, I claim to be no expert in this field. I'm just a student who's been through the process and wants to help others navigate it. So take my very opinionated advice with a grain of salt.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="research--development-vs-development"&gt;&lt;span style="color:#FFB4A2"&gt;Research &amp;amp; Development vs. Development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When planning your FYP, it’s essential to decide which type of project best aligns with your interests, skills, and career goals. Generally, there are two broad categories:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>